matterport.com 2019-12-04

# Privacy Policy - Matterport

Please note that, by using this website, the services available on this website, and the mobile and desktop applications, including virtual reality (“VR”) and augmented reality (“AR”) applications (collectively, the “Services”) provided by Matterport, Inc. (“Matterport”), you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Services. 

For the purposes of EU data protection laws ("Data Protection Legislation"), Matterport is data controller (i.e., the company who is responsible for, and controls the processing of, your personal data). 

### What is the purpose of this Privacy Policy?

This Privacy Policy discloses our personal information gathering and dissemination practices with respect to the Services. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. By visiting and/or using the Services, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

### What information do we collect from users and how is it used?

This section describes the types of personal information we may collect about you, and how we use that information. We use the personal information we collect to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us; to improve our services; to provide you with information about other goods and services we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about; or to notify you about changes to our Services. 

**Information you provide to us directly.** We may collect personal information, such as your name, phone number, address, industry, company and e-mail address when you when you register for our Services, sign up for our mailing list, or otherwise communicate with us. 

**Payment and transaction information.** Information such as camera purchased and subscription plans, date and time of your transaction, and payment information, such as your credit card or bank account details. We use this information to facilitate transactions, detect and prevent fraud and inform our advertising and marketing. 

**Online Inquiries.** When you submit an inquiry via the Services, we may ask for your first and last name, physical address, email address, phone number, company name, industry type, and certain other information from time to time. We request this information for identification purposes, and to communicate with you regarding your inquiry. If you provide your phone number, we may use that information to make direct dial calls, autodialed and prerecorded message calls, and to send text messages, from Matterport relating to our product and services. 

**Correspondence.** If you correspond with us via email, we may gather in a file specific to you the information that you submit. 

**Images stored.** When you capture imagery and submit it to the Matterport Cloud (as described in the Matterport Cloud Subscription Agreement), we may collect personal information which is depicted within the imagery you submit. We do use this information in aggregated form for analytics and machine learning, but the results of these activities do not contain or disclose any personal information that is identifiable to you. We do not use this incidental information for any other purpose, but this information may be publicly displayed if you choose to display the underlying imagery publicly through the Matterport Cloud. If you do not wish to publicly display personal information depicted in the imagery you submit, you should either refrain from capturing such personal information in your imagery or designate the imagery as “private” in your Matterport Cloud account. For additional information on designating your imagery as “public” or “private”, restricting third parties from editing or re-sharing your imagery, and the consequences of archiving your imagery, deleting your imagery and/or terminating your account, please also see the Matterport Cloud Subscription Agreement. We will store your imagery for the longer of (i) the period of your subscription to the Matterport Cloud or (ii) 10 years from the date of first import into the Matterport Cloud. 

**URL, IP addresses, Device Information and Frequency of Use.** Like many other online service providers, we collect and analyze information about our users’ utilization and navigation of our Services. This information helps us to design our Services to better suit our users’ needs, and we also use this information to share aggregated, anonymous information on the effectiveness of our Services with content owners and creators. 

We track and collect data about how frequently you use the Services, the time You spend actively using the Services, and the pattern of actions you take in using the Services, We also track the URL that you visited before you came to our Services, the URL to which you next go, information about the browser through which you are accessing the Services, and your Internet Protocol (IP) address. We use this information to help diagnose problems with our Services and to administer our Services. Your IP address also is used to help identify you and to gather broad location and demographic information. 

Our mobile applications also track and provide to us data about the ID and make/model of the mobile device that runs the app. The mobile applications will track information when you are online, and may also track information when you are offline. 

### Legal basis for processing in the EU 

If you are a resident in the EU, we need to tell you the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information. In the EU, the purposes for which we process your personal data are: 

  1. Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you for the Service; 
  2. Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests; and 
  3. Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation in the EU.

We may ask for your consent for processing your personal information in relation to the Services, in certain cases. You should be aware that you are entitled under Data Protection Legislation to withdraw your consent where that has been given, at any time. If you do this and we have no alternative lawful reason to process your personal data, this may affect our ability to provide you with rights to use the Services. In summary, we need certain categories of personal data in order to provide you with the Services. Certain other personal data is processed for our legitimate interests in cases where this does not result in prejudice to you. Certain other personal data is processed based on consent. 

We have set out in the table at Annex 1 a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal basis we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one legal basis has been set out. 

### Cookies and similar technologies 

Our website and Matterport Cloud use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Service. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve the Service. 

Cookies are pieces of code that allow for personalisation of the Service experience by saving your information such as user ID and other preferences. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. For more information, please refer to our cookie policy at [www.matterport.com/legal/cookie-policy/](https://www.matterport.com/legal/cookie-policy/)

### Marketing and advertising

From time to time, we may contact you with information about our products and services. Most marketing messages we send will be by email. For some marketing messages, we may use personal information we collect about you to help us determine the most relevant marketing information to share with you. If you do not want to receive marketing messages from us, you will be able to tell us by selecting certain boxes on forms we use when we first collect your contact details. You can also change your marketing preferences at a later date by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our marketing emails or logging into your account on our website and changing your preferences. 

### To whom we disclose information about you that we collect?

Matterport will not share, rent, sell or otherwise disclose any of the personal information that we collect about you, except when we have your permission or in any of the following situations: 

We disclose information that we collect about you to our third-party contractors who perform services for Matterport in connection with the Services and/or our business, or to complete or confirm a transaction that you conduct with us. Unless you request otherwise, we require these contractors to use or disclose this information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by law. 

We may disclose the results of aggregated data about you for marketing or promotional purposes, as further described below. We may disclose, to the owners of certain content available through the Services, or their representatives, the following types of aggregated data about usage of such content: the number of views and the number of users who view the content, statistical information about users who view the content by geography, the referring URLs of users who view the content, the number of users who interacted with the content in specific ways, and other similar aggregated information relating to usage of the content. We may also disclose to third parties certain algorithms developed from analytics and machine learning conducted on user information collected in aggregated form, but these algorithms do not contain or disclose any personal information that is identifiable to you. 

We may disclose information about you as part of a bankruptcy, corporate reorganization, merger, acquisition or other sale or transfer of Matterport’s assets or business. We may be legally obligated to disclose information about you to the government or to third parties under certain circumstances, such as in connection with illegal activity in connection with our Services or to respond to a subpoena, court order or other legal process. We reserve the right to release information that we collect to law enforcement or other government officials, as we, in our sole and absolute discretion, deem necessary or appropriate. 

###  Where do we process your personal information?

  * International Transfers of your personal information. As we are primarily located in the USA, any information you provide will initially be collected processed and stored in the USA. If you are in the EU or EEA, this may mean that your personal information will be stored in a jurisdiction that offers a level of protection that may, in certain instances, be less protective of your personal information than the jurisdiction you are typically resident in. 
  * Privacy Shield. We comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. privacy framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information received from European Union countries and Switzerland (the "Privacy Shield"). We have certified that we adhere to the Privacy Principles of notice, choice and accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity, purpose limitation, access, and recourse, enforcement and liability ("Principles"). If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Principles shall govern. In cases of onward transfers of data received pursuant to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, we are potentially liable. To learn more about Privacy Shield, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce Privacy Shield website: https://www.privacyshield.gov/. For more information regarding our Privacy Shield certification, please see: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>. 
  * If you wish to enquire further about the safeguards we use, please contact us using the details set out at the end of this Privacy Policy. 
  * We will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with applicable law and this Privacy Policy. 
  * Jurisdiction and Enforcement 
  * As part of our participation in the Privacy Shield, we are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission ("FTC"). 
  * For European Union residents, you also have the right to lodge a complaint to your local data protection authority. Further information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>. 
  * In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, we commit to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy should first contact us using the contact information listed below.
  * We have further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism. Under certain conditions specified by the Principles, you may also be able to invoke binding arbitration to resolve your complaint. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit JAMS at <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information and to file a complaint.

### How do we use online analytics services and tailored online marketing?

In our Services, we use Google Analytics and other third-party web analytics services. These third-party services use the sort of technology described in the preceding sections to help us analyze how users use the Services, including by noting the URL that users visited before they came to our Services. These service providers will receive or directly collect the information collected by the technology, which they will use to evaluate your use of the Services. As described in the following paragraphs, we also use Google Analytics on this website, and in the services available through this website (collectively, the “Site”) for certain purposes related to online marketing. You may click here to install the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on to prevent Google Analytics from using your information for analytics on the Site. 

We also allow other third parties, such as Google Analytics and other ad networks and ad servers, to access their own cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, mobile phone, or other device you use to access the Site. These tracking technologies enable these third parties to serve our tailored marketing to you while viewing other areas of the Internet, based on anonymous information collected while you are visiting our Site. We have implemented the following Google Analytics advertising features based on interests and location for the purposes of remarketing: retargeting and enhanced demographic tracking, including affinity audiences, custom affinity audiences, in-market audiences, similar audiences, demographic and location targeting, and demographics and interest reports. The parties that provide these technologies may offer you a way to opt out of targeted marketing as described below. Click here for more information on how Google uses data when you use the Site. 

You may visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s Consumer Opt-Out Link and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Consumer Opt-Out Link to opt-out of receiving tailored marketing from companies that participate in those programs, and if you are interested in learning about tailored browser marketing and how you can generally control cookies from being put on your computer to deliver tailored marketing (i.e., not just for our Site). You may also visit the Google Ads Settings page to opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising or customize Google Display Network ads. Please also see additional information here about Google Ad Settings for mobile apps. Be aware that you may still receive marketing content that is not tailored to your interests, even if you opt-out of tailored marketing, to the extent marketing technology is integrated into our Site. In addition, we are not responsible for any choices you make using any of the above opt-out links, and we do not control these opt-out methods or their continued availability or accuracy. 

You may also receive tailored in-application marketing content when using an application on a mobile device. Each mobile operating system provides its own instructions on how to prevent or opt-out of the delivery of tailored in-application marketing content. California privacy disclosures 

California law requires us to let you know how we respond to web browser Do Not Track (DNT) signals. Because there currently isn’t an industry or legal standard for recognizing or honoring DNT signals, we don’t respond to them at this time. We await the result of work by the privacy community and industry to determine when such a response is appropriate and what form it should take. 

A California resident who has provided personal information to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes (“California Customer”) is entitled to request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, subject to certain exceptions. In general, subject to certain exceptions, if the business has made such a disclosure of personal information, upon receipt of a request by a California Customer, the business is required to provide, free of charge, a list of all third parties to whom personal information was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of personal information that were disclosed. California Customers may request further information about our compliance with this law using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy. 

### EU privacy rights

If you are located in the EU, you have the following rights in respect of your personal data that we hold: 

  * Right of access. The right to obtain access to your personal data.
  * Right to rectification. The right to obtain rectification of your personal data without undue delay where that personal data is inaccurate or incomplete. 
  * Right to erasure. The right to obtain the erasure of your personal data without undue delay in certain circumstances, such as where the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed.
  * Right to restriction. The right to obtain the restriction of the processing undertaken by us on your personal data in certain circumstances, such as where the accuracy of the personal data is contested by you, for a period enabling us to verify the accuracy of that personal data.
  * Right to portability. The right to portability allows you to move, copy or transfer personal data easily from one organization to another. 
  * Right to object. You have a right to object to processing based on legitimate interests and direct marketing. 

If you wish to exercise one of these rights, please contact us using the contact details at the end of this Privacy Policy. 

You also have the right to lodge a complaint to your local data protection authority. Further information about how to contact your local data protection authority is available at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm>. 

### What security measures do we employ for the Services?

To help protect the privacy of data you transmit through the Services, where personal information is requested, we use technology designed to encrypt the information that you input before it is sent to us. In addition, we take commercially reasonable steps to protect data that we collect through the Services against unauthorized access. However, you should keep in mind that the Services is run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may, from time to time, require maintenance or experience problems or breaches of security beyond our control. 

Please also be aware that despite our best intentions and the guidelines outlined in this Privacy Policy, no data transmission over the Internet or encryption method can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

### How long do you retain personal information?

Unless otherwise specifically stated elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, we will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. 

### How can you correct or update information that we collect about you?

You may correct or update information collected about you by contacting Matterport at the email or mailing address noted below. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to correct or update our records. For our records, we may retain original and updated information for reasons such as technical constraints, dispute resolution, troubleshooting, and agreement enforcement. 

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by contacting us at the email address below. 

You have the right to access personal information about you. We may request a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you, as permitted by law. We may decline to process requests that are frivolous, vexatious, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or not otherwise required by local law. 

### What are the policies of third-party websites, apps or services?

This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of personal information collected from you by Matterport. You should be aware that when you are using the Services, you may also use or be directed to other websites, applications or services of third parties that are beyond our control, and Matterport is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties or the content of their websites, applications or services. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policy whenever interacting with any third party website, application or service. 

### How will I know about changes in the Privacy Policy?

Matterport reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time, with such changes to be effective from the moment a revised Privacy Policy is posted on this website. Please visit this page periodically so that you will be apprised of any changes. 

### What is our policy on children users of the Services?

We do not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from persons under 13 years old. Our Services are intended for use by a general audience, and no part of our Services is directed to children under 13. If Matterport learns that personal information of children less than 13 years old has been collected without verifiable parental consent, then Matterport will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained an account on the Services or otherwise provided us with personal information without your consent, then you may alert Matterport at the address below and request that we delete that child’s personal information from our systems. 

### What law governs my use of the Services?

By choosing to use the Services or otherwise to provide information to Matterport, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Policy will be governed by the law of the State of California. You also agree to abide by any limitation on damages contained in the Matterport Terms of Use or other agreement that we have with you. 

### How can you contact us?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or need to reach us for any other reason, you may contact us by e-mail at privacy@matterport.com or by mail at: 

Matterport, Inc.  
352 E. Java Dr.  
Sunnyvale, CA 94089  

 ** _Annex 1_**

 ** _Legal basis for processing in the EU_ >**

Category of personal information| Purpose /Activity| Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
 **Contact information and basic personal details** such as your first name, last name, phone number, e-mail address and date of birth. |  We use this information to operate, maintain and provide to you the features of the Service.| The processing is necessary for: 

  * the performance of a contract and to take steps prior to entering into a contract; 
  * our legitimate interests, namely administering the Service, for marketing purposes and communicating with users.

We use this information to communicate with you, including sending Service-related communications (such as invoices and information about updates to the Service, and any news, alerts and marketing communications (in line with your settings and options)).| The processing is necessary for: 

  * the performance of the contract and to take steps prior to entering into a contract; and 
  * our legitimate interests, namely administering the Service, for marketing purposes and communicating with users.

We use this information to deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to the Service.| The processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, namely administering the Service, for marketing purposes and communicating with users.  
 **Payment and transaction** information including information such as camera purchased and subscription plans, payment information (such as your credit or debit card details or your bank account details), and time, date and value of transactions. | We use this information to facilitate transactions and provide you with the Service.| The processing is necessary for the performance of a contract.  
We use this information to provide customer support.| The processing is necessary for: 

  * the performance of the contract and to take steps prior to entering into a contract; and 
  * our legitimate interests, namely administering the Service.

We use this information to detect and prevent fraud.| >The processing is necessary for our legitimate interests, namely the detection and prevention of fraud.  
 **Images stored.** When you capture imagery and submit it to the Matterport Cloud (as described in the Matterport Cloud Subscription Agreement), we may collect personal information which is depicted within the imagery you submit.| We use this information to operate, maintain and provide to you the features of the Service. | The processing is necessary for: 

  * the performance of a contract and to take steps prior to entering into a contract; and 
  * our legitimate interests, namely administering the Service, for marketing purposes and communicating with users.
